Finding Aid for the June Wayne Papers LSC.0562
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 12: Artwork Photographs, 1936-2007
  - Subseries 3: Paintings, 1936-1995
    - Night Swim, 1969 (Box 149, Folder 22)
      1 8x10" negative, 3 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 2 4x5" transparencies, 2 3.75x4.25" photographs. Includes one photograph of the painting in-progress.
    - Noon Tidal Pull, 1973 (Box 149, Folder 23)
      1 8x10" negative, 2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" transparencies, 1 4x5" photograph.
    - Northridge, 1994 (Box 149, Folder 24)
      1 8x10" photograph, 1 4x5" negative, 3 4x5" transparencies, 1 4x5" photographs.
    - Olivero, 1995 (Box 149, Folder 25)
      1 8x10" photograph, 1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" transparency, 1 4x5" photograph.
    - Pewter Byte, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 26)
      1 Polaroid.
    - Port, 1989 (Box 149, Folder 27)
    - Printout, 1973 (Box 149, Folder 28)
      1 8x10" negative, 7 4x5" transparencies, 3 4x5" photographs.
    - Prismatic Flower, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 29)
    - Pt. Dume Scanador, 1994 (Box 149, Folder 30)
    - The Quiet One, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 31)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 5x7" transparency, 1 4x5" negative, 1 bookplate.
    - Rhed, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 32)
      3 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" negative, 3 4x5" transparencies, 7 4x5" photographs.
    - Rhob, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 33)
      2 8x10" photograph, 3 4x5" transparencies, 3 polaroids. 1 8x10" photograph features an installation shot of Rhob and Hel at 1108 Tamarind.
    - Sad Flute Player, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 34)
      1 4x5" negative, 2 4x5" photograph.
    - Sagh, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 35)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" photographs, 2 4x5" transparencies. One of the transparencies shows an early stage of the painting.
    - Saghex, undated (Box 149, Folder 36)
      1 4x5" transparency, 3 4x5" photographs.
    - The Saint and the Sinner, 1956 (Box 149, Folder 37)
    - The Sanctified, 1951 (Box 149, Folder 38)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 5x7" transparency, 1 4x5" transparency, 1 bookplate.
    - Scanner AC, 1987 (Box 149, Folder 39)
      1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" transparency.
    - Scanning GT, 1987 (Box 149, Folder 40)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 2 4x5" transparencies, 4 4x5" photographs.
    - Score, 1990 (Box 149, Folder 41)
      1 8x10" negative, 1 8x10" photograph, 1 4x5" negative.
    - Self Portrait, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 42)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 3 4x5" transparencies.
    - Self Portrait, 1957 (Box 149, Folder 43)
      1 4x5" photograph.
    - Shiver, 1993 (Box 149, Folder 44)
      1 8x10" negative, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" transparency, 2 4x5" photographs.
    - Silver Byte, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 45)
      3 polaroids.
    - Silver Field, 1989 (Box 149, Folder 46)
      2 4x5" transparencies.
    - Silver Palm (bottom), 1989 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Silver Palm (top), 1989 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Sixti Sexate, 1968 (Box 150, Folder 3)
      2 5x7" transparencies, 1 4x5" negative, 2 4x5" transparencies, 8 3.25x4.25" photographs.
    - Slight Distraction, 1990 (Box 150, Folder 4)
    - Slight Disturbance, 1992 (Box 150, Folder 5)
      2 8x10" photographs, 3 4x5" negatives, 3 4x5" transparencies, 10 4x5" photographs.
    - Slip, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 6)
    - Small Shock, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Sneaking up on Red, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - String Wave, 1994 (Box 150, Folder 9)
      2 8x10" photograph, 1 4x5" negative, 2 4x5" transparencies, 6 4x5" photographs.
    - Study for the Messenger, 1954 (Box 150, Folder 10)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 3 4x5" transparencies, 2 4x5" photographs.
    - The Suitor, 1952 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Sunspot, 1972 (Box 150, Folder 12)
      1 8x10" negative, 5 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 4 4x5" transparencies, 1 4x5" photograph, 2 3.25"x4.25" photographs, 1 bookplate.
    - Temblor, 1992 (Box 150, Folder 13)
      1 8x10" photograph, 1 4x5" negative, 2 4x5" transparencies.
    - Tidal Pull 4am, 1973 (Box 150, Folder 14)
      1 8x10" negative, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" negative, 3 4x5" transparencies, 1 4x5" photograph.
    - Tidal Pull 7am, 1973 (Box 150, Folder 15)
      1 8x10" negatives, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" negatives, 2 4x5" transparencies, 1 4x5" photograph.
    - The Tunnel, 1949 (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Untitled (Mexican Woman Wearing Rebozo), 1936 (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Waiting for Newspapers, 1936 (Box 150, Folder 18)
      1 8x10" photograph, 2 4x5" negatives, 2 4x5" transparencies, 3 4x5" photographs.
    - Witching Hour, 1948 (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - The Witnesses, 1956 (Box 150, Folder 20)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 5x7" transparency, 1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" transparency.
    - Zhule, 1984 (Box 150, Folder 21)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 2 4x5" transparencies, 8 4x5" photographs.
  - Subseries 4: Drawings, 1953-1996
    This subseries includes photographs of drawings made by Wayne, primarily done either early or late in her career.
    - The Assayer, 1952 (Box 150, Folder 22)
    - Daisy Chain, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 23)
    - The Man with the White Eye, 1956 (Box 150, Folder 24)
      1 8x10" negative, 1 8x10" photograph, 1 8x10" contact sheet, 1 4x5" transparency, 35mm negatives. Contact sheet and negatives also show String Wave.
    - Roller Coaster, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 25)
    - Study for Final Jury, 1953 (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - Study for Jury V, 1953 (Box 150, Folder 27)
    - Squint at Me, 1992 (Box 150, Folder 28)
    - Third Hero, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 29)
    - Third Study for a Messenger, 1954 (Box 150, Folder 30)
      1 8x10" photographs.
    - Twister, 1996 (Box 150, Folder 31)
    - Whatever Dyes was not Mixt Equally, 1958 (Box 150, Folder 32)
    - Who is so safe as wee, 1958 (Box 150, Folder 33)
  - Subseries 5: Collages, 1987-1993
    This subseries includes photographs of collages made by Wayne, some of which are included in a set, such as the Scannerite Group.
    - Eighth Ankerite, 1989 (Box 150, Folder 34)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" transparencies.
    - Empyrealite One, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 35)
    - Empyrealite Six, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 36)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 2x2" negative.
    - Empyrealite Two, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 37)
    - First Ankerite, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 38)
    - Five Bits, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 39)
    - Scanador Six, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 40)
    - Scannerite A, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 41)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives, 1 4x5" transparency, 2 4x5" photographs.
    - Scannerite B, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 42)
    - Scannerite C, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 43)
      3 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" transparencies.
    - Scannerite J, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 44)
    - Seventh Ankerite, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 45)
      2 8x10" photographs, 2 4x5" negatives.
    - Sixth Ankerite, 1987 (Box 150, Folder 46)
    - Three Bits, 1993 (Box 150, Folder 47)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" transparency, 1 2x2" negative.
    - Unique Ankerite, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 48)
  - Subseries 6: Tapestries, 1971-1976
    This subseries includes photographs of tapestries made by Wayne.
    - Cartoons, undated (Box 150, Folder 49)
      5 8x10" negatives, 1 8x10" contact sheet, 1 5x7" photograph, 36 3.5x4.25" photographs, 8 2x3" negatives, 1 2.25x2" color print.
    - Tapestries installed at 1108 Tamarind Avenue, circa 1976 (Box 151, Folder 50)
      6 2x3" color negatives. Works included in this folder are the tapestries: At Last a Thousand, Cinquieme Vague, Lame de Choc, Onde en Folie, Col Noir, Grand Vague (Bleue).
    - At Last a Thousand, 1971 (Box 150, Folder 50)
      2 8x10" photographs, 1 8x10" contact sheet, 2 detail photographs, 1 4x5" negative, 1 4x5" photograph, 12 3.5x4.25" photographs, 4 2x3" transparencies, 4 2x3" negatives, 1 bookplate negative.
    - Col Noir, 1976 (Box 150, Folder 52)
      1 8x10" negative, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4.5x5" photograph, 1 2x3" color negative.
    - La Cible (The Target), 1971 (Box 150, Folder 53)
      1 8x10" negative, 1 8x10" photograph, 1 8x10" contact sheet, 2 4x5" negatives, 1 4x5" transparency, 11 3.5x4.25" photographs, 1 2x3" transparency.
    - Cinquieme Vague (Fifth Wave), 1971 (Box 150, Folder 54)
      1 8x10" negative, 3 8x10" photographs, 3 transparencies, 1 4x5" negative, 3 2x3" color negatives, 1 bookplate.
    - Grand Vague (Bleue), 1976 (Box 150, Folder 55)
      2 8x10" negatives, 1 8x10" transparency, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4x5" transparency, 1 2x3" color negative, 1 2x3" transparency, 1 2x3" photograph.
    - Grand Vague (Noire), 1976 (Box 151, Folder 1)
      1 8 x 10" negative print, 2 6 x 9" photographs, 1 5 x 7" photograph, 1 trimmed color photograph, 1 4 x 5" transparency.
    - La Journee des Lemmings (Lemming's Day), 1971 (Box 151, Folder 2)
      1 5 x 7" negative print, 4 5 x 7" photographs, 2 4 x 5" transparencies, 2 2.5 x 3" negative prints, 1 2 x 2" transparency, 2 2.5 x 3" photographs.
    - Lame de Choc (Shock Wave), 1972 (Box 151, Folder 3)
      2 8x10" negative prints, 2 8x10" photographs, 1 4 x 5" transparency on 8x10" sheet, 2 4 x 5" negative prints, 3 5x7" photographs, 1 4 x 5.75" photograph, 1 4 x 5" transparency, 5 3.25 x 4.25" photographs, 1 2.75 x 3" color negative print, 1 2 x 2" negative print, 1 bookplate.
    - On Verra, 1972 (Box 151, Folder 4)
      1 8 x 10" negative print, 3 8 x 10" photographs, 1 8 x 10" color contact sheet, 2 trimmed 4 x 5" transparencies.
    - Onde en Folie, 1972 (Box 151, Folder 5)
      2 8 x 10" photographs, 1 5 x 7" photograph, 2 4 x 5" negative prints, 2 4 x 5" transparencies, 5 3.25 x 4.25" photographs, 1 2.75 x 3" color negative print, 1 2.75 x 3" photograph. Photographs include images of the cartoon for On Verra.
    - Verdict, 1973 (Box 151, Folder 6)
      1 8 x 10" negative print, 2 8 x 10" transparencies, 1 8 x 10" photograph, 1 6 x 9.5" photograph, 1 4 x 5" negative print, 1 4 x 5" transparency, 4 2.75 x 3" transparencies, 1 1.5 x 2.75" transparency.
    - Visa, 1972 (Box 151, Folder 7)
      1 8 x 10" negative print, 2 8 x 10" photographs, 1 5 x 7" photograph, 1 4 x 5" negative print, 3 2.75 x 3" color negative prints, 2 2.75 x 3" transparencies.
    - White Visa, 1972 (Box 151, Folder 8)
      2 5 x 7" photographs.
  - Subseries 7: Digital Files, undated
    This subseries includes CDs and DVDs that contain images of Wayne's art works.
    Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
    - Compact discs with JPEGS, undated (Box 151, Folder 9)
      7 compact discs, 12 contact sheets.
- Series 13: Writings and Public Speaking, undated
  This series has kept its original order, devised by Wayne.
  This series includes drafts and reprints of articles, speeches, and essays written by Wayne. Also included are short stories Wayne had written early in her career as an artist, as well as transcripts of interviews given by Wayne, one of which is most notably the transcripts of a UCLA oral history interview.
  - Inventory of Essays and Drafts, undated (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Early Drafts -- Various Topics for Possible Use, 2001-2006 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - 1996, 1998 and 2010 Versions of Various Articles, 1996-12008 (Box 194, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Data and Clippings, 1992-1997 (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Obituaries -- New York Times and Los Angeles Times, 1996-1997 (Box 185, Folder 3)
  - Ideas for Articles, undated (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - Letter about Clinton Adams -- Rough Draft, 2002 (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Shaping a Life -- Rough Drafts, 2000 (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - Shaping a Life -- Rutgers University, 2000 (Box 194, Folder 7)
  - The Silent Spring of the Arts, 1995 (Box 194, Folder 8)
  - The Male Artist as Stereotypical Female -- Edits and Drafts, undated (Box 194, Folder 9)
  - The Male Artist as Stereotypical Female -- Possible Edit, 1989 December (Box 194, Folder 10)
  - The Creative Process -- Possible Edit, undated (Box 194, Folder 11)
  - The Creative Process -- Third Version, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 12)
  - Edits to "The Creative Process" and "The Male Artist as a Stereotypical Female" -- Made by Alicia, 1998 (Box 194, Folder 13)
  - Archives of American Art -- Paul Cummings Interview of June Wayne, 1970 August 4 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Archives of American Art -- Paul Cummings Interview of June Wayne, 1981 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Archives of American Art -- Photos for Cummings Interview, 1948-1992 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - Archives of American Art -- Cummings Interview (Re-edited), 1994-1996 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - You and Modern Art -- Script for Recording, Session 9, circa 1953 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - You and Modern Art, 1954 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Foundation Gamesmanship, 1966 May 21-22 (Box 195, Folder 7)
  - The Art of Selling Art, 1966 September 7-9 (Box 195, Folder 8)
  - New Careers in the Arts -- Final and Edits, 1966 October 15 (Box 195, Folder 9)
  - Livre de Luxe, 1967 March 7 (Box 195, Folder 10)
  - Livre de Luxe Manuscript, 1967 April (Box 195, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of Back Stage at Royce, 1968 (Box 195, Folder 12)
  - Notes for Speech at University of Iowa, Iowa City, 1970 February 10 (Box 195, Folder 13)
  - Forwards for Tamarind Publications, 1972 (Box 195, Folder 14)
  - Los Angeles Times Piece for Henry Seldis, 1972 (Box 195, Folder 15)
  - "June Wayne" by Stephen Longstreet, 1974 (Box 195, Folder 16)
  - Learn to Say Goodbye, 1974 December 27 (Box 195, Folder 17)
  - Speech on Oral History for ARLIS - CAA, 1978 (Box 195, Folder 18)
  - CAA Convocation Speech, 1990 February 16 (Box 195, Folder 19)
  - The View from Inside, 1984 (Box 195, Folder 20)
  - The View from Inside, 1985 (Box 195, Folder 21)
  - 25th Anniversary of Tamarind: Lecture at UCLA, 1984 December 2 (Box 195, Folder 22)
  - Hard Choices: Making Art in 1986, 1986 October (Box 195, Folder 23)
  - Sensuality and the Visual Arts: Purity, Pleasure or Prurience?, circa 1987 (Box 195, Folder 24)
  - Goodbye Lousie -- Finished Edit, 1988 (Box 195, Folder 25)
  - Leonardo da Vinci Research, undated (Box 195, Folder 26)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Original Version of Article, 1989-1990 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Early Version of Article, 1989 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Delivered at Print Council of Australia, 1989 March 25 (Box 196, Folder 3)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Delivered at Tamarind Print Symposium, 1990 June (Box 196, Folder 4)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Delivered at Grunwald Center, 35th Anniversary, 1991 September 29 (Box 196, Folder 5)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes -- Delivered at Gonzaga University, 1993 April 15 (Box 196, Folder 6)
  - Broken Stones and Whooping Cranes, 1989 (Box 196, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to a Tamarind History Show, 1985 (Box 196, Folder 8)
  - Atlanta Doctorate Acceptance Speech, 1988 May 13 (Box 196, Folder 9)
  - Between the Last Word and the First Blow -- Drafts, 1990 November 2 (Box 196, Folder 10)
  - Review of "Ruth Weisberg: Prints. Mid-Life Catalogue Raisonne", 1991 April (Box 196, Folder 11)
  - Walking Backwards in the 21st Century -- 3 Versions, 1991 (Box 196, Folder 12)
  - The Artist and the Two-Faced Clock -- Graduation Speech at Pennsylvania Academy of the Arts, 1991 May (Box 196, Folder 13)
  - Speech at Gonzaga University, 1993 (Box 196, Folder 14)
  - Generations of Mentors -- Speech at Fresno Art Museum, 1994 (Box 196, Folder 15)
  - Tamarind Publications Written by June Wayne, undated (Box 196, Folder 16)
  - Genetic Code Research Material, undated (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Research on Scrolls: Metal Bars, Glues, Canvas, undated (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - Preparing Manuscripts, undated (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - Research on Lemmings, undated (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - Research on Creative Process, undated (Box 197, Folder 5)
  - The Creative Process -- Drafts, 1975-1976 (Box 197, Folder 6)
  - The Creative Process -- Corrected, 1975 (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - The Creative Process -- Draft Sent to Jehanne Teilhut, 1976 February 4 (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - The Creative Process -- Drafts of Forward, 1998 (Box 197, Folder 9)
  - Do Not Go Gentle, Van Gogh -- Speech at University of Iowa, 1970 February 10 (Box 197, Folder 10)
  - KPFK Interview Transcript -- Pasadena Museum Opening, undated (Box 197, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Artists and Feminine Sterotypes, undated (Box 197, Folder 12)
  - Articles by Alexander Franz on Psychoanalysis and Art, undated (Box 197, Folder 13)
  - Drafts of a Speech About Artists and Curators, undated (Box 197, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Weaving the Tapestries in France, undated (Box 197, Folder 15)
  - Notes on Creativity, undated (Box 197, Folder 16)
  - Research on Creativity, undated (Box 197, Folder 17)
  - Research on Creativity, undated (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Whose Obit is it Anyhow?, 1996-1997 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Memorial to Maurice Bloch, 1990 January 26 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Memorial for Ebria Feinblatt, 1990 September 9 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - On the Death of Joyce Treiman, 1991 (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Mac Lowry Tribute, 1993 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - WGN Radio Scripts, 1942-1943 (Box 198, Folder 7)
  - Radio Scripts, 1943 (Box 198, Folder 8)
  - Music that Endures: Radio Program, 1943 March 31 (Box 198, Folder 9)
  - Pickel Pronounced Pickell, 1942 (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - Fire a Burst of Six, 1942 (Box 198, Folder 11)
  - Siegfried with a Tic -- Short Story, 1942 (Box 198, Folder 12)
  - The Inspection, 1943 (Box 198, Folder 13)
  - Manuscripts by Harold Jacobsen, 1949 (Box 198, Folder 14)
  - Rapture and the Bends Files, undated (Box 198, Folder 15)
  - Rapture and the Bends Proposal, undated (Box 198, Folder 16)
  - Rapture and the Bends Draft, undated (Box 198, Folder 17)
  - Research Materials -- Rapture of the Deep, 1996 (Box 185, Folder 5)
  - The Arts and the Sound Bite that Kills, 1990 (Box 198, Folder 18)
  - Avant Garde Mindset in the Artist's Studio -- Drafts, 1985-1987 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Avant Garde Mindset in the Artist's Studio, 1985 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Virtual Reality and "The Big One", 1984 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Senefelder Drafts, 1970-1998 (Box 185, Folder 6)
  - Senefelder Drafts, 1998 October 8 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Senefelder in Silicon Valley, 1997 January 27 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - Senefelder in Silicon Valley -- Cal State Long Beach, 1998 July 8 (Box 199, Folder 6)
  - What's All this Kissing at my Vernissage?, 1999 (Box 199, Folder 7)
  - Walking Backward into the 21st Century, 1992 (Box 199, Folder 8)
  - Inside the Outside: An Artist's New Deal Heritage, 1987 (Box 199, Folder 9)
  - Inside the Outside -- Notes for Speech at Hillsdale College, 1988 December 16 (Box 199, Folder 10)
  - Editorial Notes, undated (Box 199, Folder 11)
  - Editorial Notes, undated (Box 199, Folder 12)
  - Leonardo and I, 1988 March 28 (Box 199, Folder 13)
  - June Wayne Bibliography, 199 January (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - June Wayne Bibliography, 2000 June (Box 200, Folder 2)
  - UCLA Oral History I, 1976-1991 (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - UCLA Oral History II, 1976 January 21 (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - UCLA Oral History III, 1976 January 28 (Box 200, Folder 5)
  - UCLA Oral History IV, 1976 February 4 (Box 200, Folder 6)
  - UCLA Oral History V, 1976 February 11 (Box 200, Folder 7)
  - UCLA Oral History VI, 1976 February 16 (Box 200, Folder 8)
  - UCLA Oral History VII, 1976 March 3 (Box 200, Folder 9)
  - UCLA Oral History VIII, 1976 March 9 (Box 200, Folder 10)
  - UCLA Oral History IX, 1976 March 31 (Box 200, Folder 11)
  - UCLA Oral History X, 1976 April 9 (Box 200, Folder 12)
  - UCLA Oral History Restricted Pages, 1976-1982 (Box 200, Folder 13)